LOUIS PHAM

Full-stack developer

Contact Information

louis.c.pham@gmail.com

.....

- **J** 416 912 5292
- Mississauga, Ontario

Profiles

louispham.dev

github.com/louis-pham

in linkedin.com/in/louispham

Full stack developer passionate about clean, straight-forward design that harmonizes with the user experience. Being involved in dance and science, creative experimentation hand in hand with contemplative analysis help me unravel a problem and develop sensible solutions.

Technical Skills

Strong: JavaScript (ES6) • HTML5 • CSS3 • Node.js • Express • Python

Knowledgeable: MongoDB • Mongoose • PostgreSQL • Django • Java • React • jQuery • Bootstrap

Work Experience

Assistant Language Teacher, Link Interac Inc. | 2017 - 2019 | Yokohama, Japan

- Created and executed lesson plans to facilitate and cultivate an interest of international cultures and the English language

Researcher, Canadian Institute for Theoretical Astrophysics | 2016 - 2017 | Toronto, Canada

- Modified simulation tool LensPix with extra functionality, Python wrappers, analysis scripts, etc.
- Tested and debugged to ensure simulation outputs were in line with theoretical expectations

Student Developer, University of Toronto KPE Faculty | 2015 - 2016 | Toronto, Canada

- Built online Sports Hall of Fame's front end and API for Drupal back end
- Overhauled physicians' electronic health forms with new capabilities and responsive design
- Created schedule displays showing events/programs for campus' athletic facilities, improving patron experience
- Developed "wayfinder" displays to provide directions, weather, and ongoing events
- Created room search tools to assist faculty in setting up meetings

Software Developer Co-op, Canada Health Infoway | 2014 - 2015 | Toronto, Canada

- Built and managed InfoScribe, a Java-based collaboration tool built off Atlassian's Confluence
- Updated interface and capabilities of AngularJS search tool HL7 Explorer
- Updated AngularJS of mockup clinical requirements and specification pages

Personal Projects

loU2: "Household-based" <u>budgeting tracker</u> built with Python + Django, PostgreSQL and AWS S3 **Dance Events**: <u>Event page</u> built with Node.js, Express, MongoDB/Mongoose and Passport OAuth2 **Battleship**: <u>Browser-based game</u> showcasing DOM manipulation, MVC design and searching

Education

Software Engineering Immersive, General Assembly I 11/2019 - 02/2020

B.Sc. with Honours in Computer Science and Astrophysics, University of Toronto I 2011 - 2017

Personal Interests dance, piano, music, astronomy, video games, technology